Ryan Snow

Masters of Science

snow4964@gmail.com \bigcirc 856-313-6653 \bigcirc snow942.github.io

Personal Statement

Molecular biologist with special interest in the environment, as well as microbial ecology and nutrient cycling. Experienced in microbiological, molecular, and computational biological settings. Determined to learn and apply new and learned skills, concepts, and techniques. Dependable, organized, capable of independent and collaborative work.

Notable Skills & Experiences

Biological

- Educator
- Cell line maintenance
- Polymerase Chain Reaction
- Bacterial ligation

Computational

- R and RStudio
 - o Tidyverse
- Git and GitHub
- Bash

- Molecular protocol review
- DNA extraction
- Transformation assays
- Field sampling
- Genomics
 - Next-Gen Sequencing
- Transciptomics
- Excel

Professional History

Associate Scientist II, NGS

Azenta Life Sciences

- Quality control analysis of DNA and RNA samples
- Use of TapeStation to verify ribosomal regions of interest

Feb 2024 to Present

South Plainfield, NJ

Lab ResearcherRutgers University

Dec 2022 to Dec 2023 New Brunswick, NJ

- Assisted with graduate student and staff research projects
- Implementation of practice to preserve, protect, and archive research data
- Configuration of historic and modern molecular lab spaces
- Molecular biology specialist for lab

Lab Researcher Dec 2022 to Oct 2023

University of California, Santa Cruz

Remote

- Research project
 - Comparative mitogenomic analysis exploring the impacts of climate change across a temporal scale
- Design of historic and contemporary molecular biology lab spaces
- Reviewer and editor of lab methodologies
- Provided feedback for graduate student projects and presentations

Molecular Technologist I

May 2022 to Oct 2022

American Red Cross, National Molecular Laboratory

Philadelphia, Pennsylvania

- Extraction of patient DNA samples
- Amplification of targeted DNA regions via PCR
- Microarray assay performed to identify the genotype and phenotype of patient hematological antibodies
- Writer and evaluator of FDA approved reports for BeadChip assays
- Analysis of patient DNA sequences for SNP identification

Research Assistant

Sep 2019 to Aug 2021

Camden, New Jersey

Rutgers University

- Research projects
 - Bioengineering E. coli energy metabolic mechanism for induction of cold tolerance
 - Icelandic bdelloidea transcriptomic profiling through differential expression analysis
- Ligation and transformation of mutated genes of interest
- RNA-Seq and differential expression analysis
- Gene enrichment and physiological analysis

Teaching Assistant

Sep 2019 to May 2021

Rutgers University

Camden, New Jersey

- Preparation of media and bacterial cultures for lab exercises
- Undergraduate lab instructor for basic microbiological techniques and core principles
- Assured students comprehended and properly applied microbiological lab techniques

Certifications

• R Boot Camp for Ecologists and Wildlife Biologists (2023) *Center for Wildlife Studies*

Education

Masters of Science: Biology

2019 to 2021

Rutgers University

Camden, New Jersey

Thesis: Icelandic bdelloidea transcriptomic profiling through differential expression analysis

Bachelors of Science: Biology

2014 to 2018

Rutgers University

Camden, New Jersey